同じ寮で暮らすことになり
困ったことになったと思った
Though I want you to stay with me always,
itsumo koko ni ite hoshii kuse ni
i
tsu
mo
拾った猫をきかけ話すようになり
When she moved into our dorm,
I thought I was in for a headache.
ko
ni
i
二年も同じグラスになった
te
ho
shi
i
ku
se
ni
After using a homeless cat as an excuse to talk to him,
I'm unable to reveal how I feel.
itsumo koko ni ite hoshii kokoro kakushita
i
学校の問題児を集めたさくら荘
tsu
mo
I ended up in the same class as him for two years.
ko
ni
i
te
ho
shi
i
ko
Former Freeloading Girl
ro
ka
ku
shi
ta
けど、近くにいるせいで
Sakura-sou, where the school's problem children reside.
On days when I'm alone and can't see you,
aenakunatta samishii hi mo
a
e
na
ku
前より言えなくなった
na
tta
sa
mi
shi
i
hi
mo
I want to know how you feel.
kimochi tashikametai
ki
mo
chi
ta
shi
この気持ちを口に出すのが
ka
me
ta
But because she was so close,
it became harder than ever to tell her.
i
ずっと難しくになった
You're so close that I can reach out and touch you,
te wo nobaseba fureau kyori nano ni
te
wo
no
ba
se
fu
re
a
u
kyo
ri
na
It became harder than ever for me to put my emotions into words.
no
ni
yet I'm afraid to take that step.
sono ippo ga fumidasenai watashi
so
no
i
p
po
ga
fu
mi
da
se
na
i
wa
ta
shi
When I close my eyes, they brim over with sadness.
me wo tojitara setsunasa ga koboresou de
me
wo
to
ji
ta
ra
se
tsu
na
sa
ga
ko
bo
re
so
u
de
I call your name again
I
call
your
name
a
gain
I call your name again
I
call
your
name
a
gain
o
j
n
a
K
n
t
e
P
o
n
u
o
s
-
a
r
u
k
a
S
Sakura-sou no Pet na Kanojo
Kanda Sorata
Would you be able
to vacate the dorm,
just for Christmas Eve?
Akasaka
Ryuunosuke
Why do you ask?
Kanda Sorata
Do you want to know why?
Would you be able to vacate the dorm, just for Christmas Eve?
イプのよるだけでいい
寮を空けてくれないか？
Why do you ask?
なぜだ？
Kanda Sorata
Would you be able
to vacate the dorm,
just for Christmas Eve?
Akasaka
Ryuunosuke
Why do you ask?
Kanda Sorata
Do you want to know why?
No, I'm not interested.
Fine, I'll figure
something out.
Do you want to know why?
Kanda Sorata
Would you be able
to vacate the dorm,
just for Christmas Eve?
Akasaka
Ryuunosuke
Why do you ask?
Kanda Sorata
Do you want to know why?
No, I'm not interested.
Fine, I'll figure
something out.
Kanda Sorata
Would you be able
to vacate the dorm,
just for Christmas Eve?
Akasaka
Ryuunosuke
Why do you ask?
Kanda Sorata
Do you want to know why?
No, I'm not interested.
Fine, I'll figure
something out.
Kanda Sorata
Would you be able
to vacate the dorm,
just for Christmas Eve?
Akasaka
Ryuunosuke
Why do you ask?
Kanda Sorata
Do you want to know why?
No, I'm not interested.
Fine, I'll figure
something out.
Kanda Sorata
Would you be able
to vacate the dorm,
just for Christmas Eve?
Akasaka
Ryuunosuke
Why do you ask?
Kanda Sorata
Do you want to know why?
No, I'm not interested.
Fine, I'll figure
something out.
理由を聞きたいか？
Kanda Sorata
Would you be able
to vacate the dorm,
just for Christmas Eve?
Akasaka
Ryuunosuke
Why do you ask?
Kanda Sorata
Do you want to know why?
No, I'm not interested.
Fine, I'll figure
something out.
Kanda Sorata
Would you be able
to vacate the dorm,
just for Christmas Eve?
Akasaka
Ryuunosuke
Why do you ask?
Kanda Sorata
Do you want to know why?
No, I'm not interested.
Fine, I'll figure
something out.
No, I'm not interested.
いや、興味ない
What did he say?
何だって
He'll "figure something out."
善処するってさあ
Do you really think it'll be all right?
本当にうまくいくかな
What about Mashiron?
真白は？
#14 　圣诞夜的窗边和万家灯火
E
v
e
'
s
W
i
n
d
o
w
s
i
d
e
Ah, right.
A
n
d
E
あ、はい、二十四日は出版社のパーディーがあるんですだから
v
e
r
y
o
n
e
'
s
L
i
g
h
t
Her publisher's holding a party on the twenty-fourth.
So now we just have to deal with Chihiro-sensei?
じゃ、後は千尋先生だけ？
Nanamin and Junior will be out on a date, so...
七海と後輩君はデートだから
Yay! I think this is going to work out!
本当だ、行けそう
It's not a date.
デートじゃありません
Mashiron's Room
Please knock
...then stop being on my mind all the time!
私の中から出て行って
I haven't had a proper talk with Shiina since then.
あれから椎名とはまともに話をしていない
Mashiron's Room
Please knock
To Sorata
What are you doing?
何やって
I'm cold.
寒い
Well, of course you are.
そりゃ寒いだろうよ
Why don't you eat this?
食えば
Is it good?
おいしいか
うん
Do you want some too, Sorata?
空田も食べる
Is it good?
おいしい？
What sort of skit is this?
何なん このコントは
It's not a skit. It's a baumkuchen.
コントではなく　バームクーヘンよ
I know that!
わかってるよ
What I'm asking is—
俺が言いたいのは
Sorata, you're angry.
空太、怒ってる
What makes you say that?
何でそんな話になるんだよ
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい
For what?
何が
Don't just apologize for no reason!
分かってないのに謝るな
Anyway, are you keeping up with your manuscripts?
それよりも原稿はいいのか
Things always get busier toward the end of the year.
年末進行とかそういういろいろあるんだろう
Sorata, you're angry.
空太、怒ってる
I already told you that I'm not!
怒ってないって言っているだろう
To Sorata
Did you hear that?
聞いていました
From beginning to end.
全部聞こえてた
How did I sound?
俺、どう見えます
If I said that you sounded like an ass,
would that satisfy you?
性格悪く見えるって言えば
満足するのか
This is your chance!
それチャンスじゃ
A confession on Christmas Eve.
イプの夜に告白　絶対
Make it happen!
And why do I have to do that?!
何でそうなるの
Why?
何で、神田君と椎名さんの間が
There's been some tension between Kanda-kun and Shiina-san lately, right?
着々をしているんでしょう
And you're going on a date with Kanda-kun on Christmas Eve!
イプの夜に七海と神田君をデートをするんでしょう
Hold on a sec! It's not a date!
って待ってよ、デートじゃないって
Kanda-kun's going to take Mashiro to her party,
and then pick her up afterward.
神田君は真白をパーディー送って
帰りも迎えに行くことになっているの
So we're just killing some time together with dinner and a play.
だから、待っている間ちょっと二人で
お芝居見て、食事するだけ
Sounds like a date to me.
つまりデートでしょう
It's not!
違うってわ
Then what is it?
じゃ、何に
A date?
デート？
See?
でしょう、何着てつもり
What are you going to wear?
I haven't given it much thought yet...
特に決めてないけれど
Make sure you wear a skirt!
絶対にスカートに取きなさいよ
うっかりで根元でダメだからね
And don't go in a denim one either, okay?
え、スカートか
A skirt...?
Cancel
Profile
Rumi-san
Delete
Delete this contact?
Cancel
If you keep studying like that, you might actually end up in Osaka U.
あんまり熱心に勉強すると
大阪の芸大に合格するぞ
Is that any way to greet your friend who's working so hard for his first choice university?
それが志望校を目指して
頑張る友人にかける言葉かね
Who's this friend of mine?
誰が友人だ
My bad. I'm your best friend, aren't I?
悪かった、親友だったな
So can I help you, Student Council President?
って、何か用か、生徒会長
That's Former President to you.
今は元だ
Are you really planning to go to Osaka?
本気に大阪行くつもりか
Did Hauhau tell you?
ハウハウに聞いたのか
You two really are close—
仲がいいこと
Never mind us.
俺達のことはいい
Are you sure about this? Being separated from her.
本当にいいのか
離れ離れになっても
Yes, I'm sure.
いいんだよ
Well, I'm sure you'll find yourself a girl to play around with as soon as you get there.
お前はな
向こうに行ってところで
遊ぶ程度の女なら
すぐ作れるだろう
But Kamiigusa will be—
でも、上井草は
I don't plan on doing that.
つくるつもりはない
I cut my ties with all the girls I've been fooling around with.
遊んでくれたお姉さん方も
全員分かれた
Also, Misaki isn't alone anymore.
それに美咲はもう
一人じゃない
You're referring to Sakura-sou?
さくら荘か
Yup.
まあ、まだ何かご不満？
Still not satisfied?
What do you want to do?
どうしたいんか
"What do I want"?
どうって
What is it that you desire to do?
お前の望みは何だ
Tell me what you wish for.
望みを言う
I want to make her come around to me.
俺は、アイツを振り向かせたいんだよ
What are you talking about?
何を言ってる
You're already the center of her world.
もう十分に振り向いてだろう
That's because she's in love with me.
それが、アイツを俺が好きだから
That's not it. I want her to see me as more than a lover.
そうじゃない
俺は恋だけじゃなく
アイツを振り向かせたいんだ
Why?
どうして
Because I genuinely love her.
本気でアイツを好きだから
Sakura-sou
How about this one?
どう、これ何で
似合ってない
It doesn't suit me...
Nonsense! You look really cute!
そんなことない
かわいいぞ
So cute that it makes me want to marry you, Nanamin—
嫁にもらいたいぐらいだよ　七海
脱いちゃうの
You're taking it off?
Hm... In that case, I'll lend you this!
ええと、じゃ、これも化しちゃう
My battle bra!
勝負下着
Junior won't be able to control himself!
後輩君も大好判
Why are you bringing up Kanda-kun?
何で神田君が出てくるんですか
And why would he be seeing me in my underwear, anyway?
って言うか、下着何て見せませんよ
Go get 'em!
ファイトだよ
No, like I said—
だから、って言うか
More importantly, are you going to be all right, Kamiigusa-senpai?
上井草先輩こそ大丈夫何ですか
With what?
何か
何かってイプの告白
What else? Your confession on Christmas Eve.
Aren't you scared, Senpai?
先輩は怖くないんですか
About telling him your feelings...
気持ちを伝えることが
What are you saying, Nanamin?
何言っているの七海
Of course I'm scared.
怖いに決まっているじゃ
I mean, I've been in love with him since grade school.
だって小学生の時に
もう仁を好きだったんよ
It took me until middle school to realize it, though.
まあ、その気持ちに気ついたのは
中学生になったからたけど
So of course I'm nervous.
そりゃ緊張するよ
If I thought about it any more, I'd give in.
ちょっとでも考えたら負けんだよ
Fear would put me on another cycle!
恐怖でまた一種なんだよ
A cycle?
一種？
I mean, I start by thinking "I can't stand it any longer! I have to tell Jin my feelings for him!"
あのね、私の気持ちが仁に
この気持ち言わなきゃ
このままじゃダメってところから
"But I'm so scared. What if I get rejected?"
でも怖い
断れたらどうしよう
"Well, I guess things are fine the way they are right now. I get to be at Jin's side, after all."
まあ、今のままでもいいかな
仁の傍にいられるし
"But I want to be more lovey-dovey with Jin!"
でも、仁とラプラプ言いたい
"Jin's already going out with someone else. What if I lose him for good?"
仁にはほかに付き合っているし
いなくなちゃらどうするしよう
And so, I end up back at square one.
ってここに戻るわけ
I think I get the idea.
何となく分かります
I've probably repeated this a hundred times since middle school.
これを中学から百種しているから
A hundred times?
百種？
Yeah. I've really gotten tired of this endless cycle.
さすがに同じ形式には諦ちゃたんよ
That's why...
だから目を瞑って飛び出すよ
I'm gonna squeeze my eyes shut and take a leap of faith!
And where's he?
そっちは
Outer space?
宇宙？
That sounds unbearable.
苦しいそうですね
Nanamin, that's so mean!
七海、最悪だよ、それ
Wait! That's not what I meant!
ああ、違います
I bet the stars are pretty up there.
星、星が綺麗ですよ
きっと
Design proposal 2
"Miniature Garden Suspense"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Rejected
"Monster Panic"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Design Proposal 1 "Train Train"
15th August Documents passed
31st August Presentation
31st August Rejection
Design proposal 2
"Miniature Garden Suspense"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Rejected
"Monster Panic"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Design proposal 2
"Miniature Garden Suspense"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Rejected
"Monster Panic"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Design proposal 2
"Miniature Garden Suspense"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Rejected
"Monster Panic"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Design proposal 2
"Miniature Garden Suspense"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Rejected
"Monster Panic"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Design proposal 2
"Miniature Garden Suspense"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Rejected
"Monster Panic"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Design proposal 2
"Miniature Garden Suspense"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Rejected
"Monster Panic"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Design proposal 2
"Miniature Garden Suspense"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Rejected
"Monster Panic"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
Design Proposal 1 "Train Train"
15th August Documents passed
31st August Presentation
31st August Rejection
Design Proposal 1 "Train Train"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
15th August Documents passed
31st August Presentation
31st August Rejection
Design Proposal 1 "Train Train"
"Let's Make A Game" Application
15th August Documents passed
31st August Presentation
31st August Rejection
15th August Documents passed
31st August Presentation
31st August Rejection
15th August Documents passed
31st August Presentation
31st August Rejection
15th August Documents passed
31st August Presentation
31st August Rejection
15th August Documents passed
31st August Presentation
31st August Rejection
15th August Documents passed
31st August Presentation
31st August Rejection
To Sorata
What's she up to again?
何なんだアイツは
To Sorata
She's just doing things her way. That's all.
真白なりに考えたんじゃないの
Chihiro-sensei...
千尋先生
Though it's not like I don't get where you're coming from either.
あんたの気持ちも分からないではないけどね
Anyone would get pissed if they saw someone slacking off while they were giving it their all.
自分が本気になっている時に
手を脱いでいる奴見りや
誰だってむかつくでしょうよ
You're a teacher!
先生は先生何ですから
Don't meddle in students' affairs when they don't want you to!
生徒は触れて欲しくないとこらに触れないてくださいよ
You're just saying that because deep down, you know the truth.
あんたもわかっているから
触れられたくないんでしょう
Mashiro isn't slacking off.
真白が手を脱いでいるわけじゃないってこと
She just doesn't know how to deal with these emotions that she's never felt before.
あの子は今まで知らなかった感情といいのかわからなくなっただけよ
What are you doing by taking it out on Mashiro
仲直りの仕方もわからない真白に
あんたまで感情中断ぶつけてどうするんよ
when she doesn't know the first thing about mending relationships?
Are you saying that I should apologize?
俺が謝れてと言うですか
Moron. You're such a child.
馬鹿、本当にガキね
In what way?
何にがですか
In the way you assume everything is always black or white.
白じゃなければ黒で言い出すところが
The world isn't that simple, you know.
そんな世の中は簡単じゃないの
Most things aren't that clear-cut.
ほとんとすべてのものが曖昧の中にある
Neither black nor white, but gray.
白や黒じゃなくて　グレー
You get me?
分かる？
What should I do then?
じゃ、どうすればいいんですか
Hell if I know.
そんなの知らないわよ
I just know that if you start rejecting everything that doesn't fit your tidy little world view,
ただ、自分ぶりそうとする一番いい形だけしか
認められない人間になると
you'll end up screwing over both yourself and those around you.
自分も周りにすること
Huh? So in the en—
結局どう言う
真白のことあんたはなんとかしなさい
Figure out how to deal with her yourself.
That's all.
以上
Because I'm on Mashiro Duty?
真白当番だからですか
Because you're a man.
男だからよ
Ah, I almost forgot. I'm closing Sakura-sou for the end of the year.
った、そうだ
今年の年末さくら荘封鎖するから
Huh?
は？
I'm running off to Australia to have some fun.
私、オスラリアで遊んでくるの
So you'll have to go back home.
だから帰省しなさい
Really? That's so sudden...
そんな、急な
And so, the day finally came.
こうして
その日はやって来る
To Sorata
The day when feelings that I don't know what to do about...
どうして言いかわからない気持ちと
...feelings that I don't know if I should convey...
届けでいいのかわからない気持ちと
...and feelings that I'm not yet ready to convey...
まだ届けないと決めている気持ちが
...will cross paths, join ways, butt heads,
交差したりはさなたり打つかたり
and miss their mark.
すれ違ったりして
Well, then I'm leaving the cake to you.
じゃ、ケーキお願いします
They said to come pick it up after five o'clock.
夕方五時以後に行きくれてって言っていました
Right.
Don't forget, please.
忘れないてくださいよ
Feast your eyes on this!
眼福　眼福　どうだい？後輩君
What do you think, Junior?
So cute that you're at a loss for words?
言葉も出ないほどかわいいか
I see! I see!
そうかそうか
It looks like you're used to all this.
何か着慣れている感じだな
I had to wear a dress for award ceremonies too...
受賞式のときも ドレス好き
だから
Here, your coat.
はい、コートも着て
Okay, Jin-san, I'm counting on you.
じゃ、仁さん、よろしくお願いします
You don't have to run.
足らなくていいかな
Misaki.
美咲
Yeah?
何に
Are you going to Sakura-sou's party too?
お前もさくら荘のパーディー出るのか
Of course!
当たり前じゃ
We'll be exchanging presents, so make sure you bring one!
プレゼント交換するとか
ちゃんと用意してくるね
Well, this is...
まずいね  これは
kinda bad.
What are you doing by taking it out on Mashiro
仲直りの仕方も分からない真白に
あんたまで感情中断ぶつけてどうするんよ
when she doesn't know the first thing about mending relationships?
Sorata.
空田
うん
That envelope...
先の封筒
It's the results from my audition.
オーディションの結果だよ
Aren't you going to read it?
見ないの
I will later.
後でみるよ
Thanks so much, Kanda-kun!
ありがとう　神田君
いええ
Don't worry about it.
I'll take the princess off your hands now.
お姫様おかりするわね
Then I'll be back for her at nine thirty.
じゃ　九時半にここで
Sure.
え　コートは預かるわ
Let me take your coat.
空太
Sorata.
えん？どうした
What is it?
Say something.
何か言って  ちゃんと　話して
Talk to me.
Is there a problem?
なにかあったの
N-No. I'll leave her with you now.
あ　あ　いええ　じゃよろしくお願いします
Shiina, make sure you greet everyone properly.
椎名　挨拶　ちゃんとしてない
Talk to me.
ちゃんと　話して
Come on! What are you doing, Aoya...ma!
あのなあ　何してるの　おいい　まああ
You don't have to act so surprised!
そこまでおどろかなくていいでしょう
S-Sorry!
わ　わるい　ちょっと意外で
I didn't expect to see you dressed like that.
I knew it. It doesn't suit me.
やっばり変
No, it's not that. You just look so different from usual.
そうじゃなくて　雰囲気違うから
How is it different?
どう違う
Well... I think that look's great too.
そうだな　そういう青山も　悪くないと思え
Really?
本当に
Yeah. I was really surprised.
うん　結構びっくりした
So it was a huge success.
じゃ　大成功だ
It's snowing!
雪
I wish those merrymaking lovebirds would just spontaneously combust...
かねがカップルのもん　はくばくしろうどう？
ぶぶぶぶぶ…
Don't hang up on me! Let me talk to Ryuunosuke!
勝手にきらないで  龙之介と話させてください
I refuse.
お断りします　ぽっどくなくせに
You must be out of your mind if you think a wench like you can set any flags with this!
こんなもの龙之介と話すなんて
非常識にもほどがあります
For goodness' sake, just let me talk to Ryuunosuke already!
いいから　龙之介を出してください
お断りします
I refuse.
Snow.
雪
Sora
Wow, it's getting really heavy.
あ　結構強くなってるよね　積もるかな
I wonder if it'll stick.
I guess a little snow never hurt anyone.
雪なら被っても大丈夫かな
Here.
はい
I'm holding it?
うん　俺
You'll be sharing my umbrella, so it's the least you could do.
私の傘に入るんだから
それくらいしてくれないと
Fine, fine.
はいはい
Did you like the play?
芝居どうだった
It was interesting.
面白かったけど
At times it took my breath away and made me feel inadequate, watching the actors.
なんかどきとしたり　悔しくなったりもした　役者さんに
Yeah, when I'm playing games, I start feeling like that too.
あ　俺もゲームやってるとき　同じようなことを思うもんだ
When I compare myself to professional actors and voice-actors,
プロな人はやっばり発声から演技から　ぜんぜん違うなあって
I can't help but feel like we're worlds apart.
All the more reason to work hard.
がんばるなきゃな　ってがんばるやつに言う言葉でもないか
Though I guess that's empty advice when you're already working hard.
Do you think I'm doing enough?
私　がんばれているかな
Sure you are.
青山は　がんばっているよ　やっばり不安？
Are you still nervous?
Can you tell?
そう見える
Kind of.
なんとなく
There's an audition in February that will decide whether or not I get hired by an agency.
二月に事務所に所属できるかを決める　オーディションがあるの
そうなんだ
I see.
And if I don't make it, I've been told to go home to Osaka.
そこで　事務所に所属できなかったら
大阪に帰ってこいって言われるんだ
うん？　ちょっと　待ってよ　どういうこと
Huh? Hey, wait a second! What do you mean?
言ったどおりよ
That's it, plain and simple.
If I don't pass the audition, I'm transferring back to Osaka.
オーディションにおちたら　転校して大阪に戻る
受かったら　事務所に所属しながらスイカにかよう
If I pass, I'll continue to attend Sui High while working for the agency.
That's—
それって
Kanda-kun...
神田君　私がいなくなったら　寂しい
If I were to leave...
would you miss me?
Don't say things like that.
そういえのをやめてくれ　青山は受かる　絶対に
You'll pass.
I'm sure of it.
There's somethin' else too...
あな　もうひとつあるんね
うん
If I pass the audition...
オーディション　もしよかったら
Then...
そのとき　うちの話　聞いてほしいね
I'll have something to tell you.
About what?
話って
それはそのとき　今はわかんない
I'll tell ya then! And not a bit before!
言ってしっまったら　どうにかなってしまうだろう
If I say it now, it'll just be askin' for trouble!
そうなのか
Is that right?
うん
Okay, I'll hear you out. I promise.
あ　わかった　聞くよ　約束する
Really?
If...
もし　もしな　そのときになっても
Just if...
the time comes and I'm still being
hesitant, I want you to say to me...
うちがうずうずしてたら　いってほしいね
"Take off into space!"
宇宙に飛び出すって
What's that supposed to mean?
なんだそれは
何でもいえない　いうってや
Don't worry about it! Just say it!
なんかよくわかんないけど　わかったよ
I don't really get it, but sure.
Hello?
もしもし
Kanda-kun, it's Ayano.
神田君　綾乃です　椎名さん　そっちにいない
Is Shiina-san with you by any chance?
Shiina?
椎名
I'm sorry. Shiina-san's disappeared.
ごめんなさい　椎名さん　いなくなってしまって
The hotel staff told me she went outside.
ホテルの人の話だと　そとにでていたって
Do you have any idea where she could have gone?
何か心当たりない
Is something wrong?
どうかしたの
Aoyama, take this!
青山　これ
Kanda-kun!
神田君
Misaki...
美咲
Answer me.
答えて　ちゃんと
Honestly.
I love you.
好きだ　好きだよ
Really?
本当に
Yeah.
あ　本気でずっと思っていた
I've felt this way for a very long time.
The snow.
雪　止んちゃった
It's stopped.
Shiina!
椎名
お前
You...
Sorata.
空太
You idiot! What are you thinking?!
馬鹿　何やったんだ
Where are your shoes?
靴はどうした
I lost them somewhere along the way.
歩いているうちにいった
"Somewhere"?!
どこかって
This is for you.
これあげる
I wanted you to have one because they're delicious.
おいしいから　空太に食べてほしくて
That's why you came outside?
それで出てきたのか
Yes.
うん
What the hell were you thinking?!
お前何に考えてたんだよ
It's because... you've been so angry lately.
だって　空太最近ずっとおこってるから
Even though there's so much I want to say to you...
私　たくさん話したいことがあるのに
you don't face me properly.
いやな顔ばかりで
I didn't want that, so I thought about what I should do...
そんなのいやだから　どうすればいいか考えて
What I should do to make you happy again.
どうすれば空太が喜んでくれるか
What I should do to lighten up the mood.
どうすれば楽しくなるのか
But I couldn't think of anything... I...
でも　わからなくて
私　これしかできない
This is all I can do.
Is it good?
おいしい
It's hard.
硬い
Are you angry?
怒ってる
Yeah, I'm definitely angry.
あ　そうだな　怒ってる
Sorata?
空太
I get worried sick when you disappear without a word.
突然黙っていなくなったら心配するんだよ
Hearing that you'd disappeared...
that you were nowhere to be found...
きゅうにいなくなったって　どこにもいないって
I was scared to death that you'd gotten in an accident.
俺交通事故に巻き込まれたんじゃないかって
心臓止まるかだとおもったんぞ
Sorata...
空太
自覚持ってよ
Take better care of yourself.
Walking around here barefoot... Cutting your finger...
こんなところ果たしてあるいたり　雪怪我したり
You're a professional manga artist, you know?
お前プロの漫画家なんだぞ
I've been thinking about you a lot.
空太のこと　よく考えてる
And when I do, I start wanting to try new things.
そしたら　してみたくなった
Things like making boxed lunches...
お弁当を作ったり　前はこんなふうに思わなかった
I've never felt this way before.
I don't understand it myself.
自分でもわからない　こんなことがなかったの
Even though it's never happened before...
I got goose bumps watching you draw your manga.
俺　お前が漫画描いてるを見て
取り計らいだんだ
It was astounding.
衝撃的だった
Without compromise or worries about the future, you drew with everything you had.
妥協とか　後のこととか
一切考えずに全力で書いてた
As if it was the most natural thing in the world, you put everything on the line.
それが当然のように　すべてをかけて
Since then, I haven't been able to take my eyes off you.
それ以来　真白から目が離せなくなった
Since then, I've grown fond of that part of you.
あのときから俺は　そういう真白がすき何だよ
So don't disappoint me.
だから俺をがっかりさせるなよ　俺はお前のことを見てる　ちゃんと見てるから
I'm watching over you, always.
Sorata...
空太
How long do the two of you plan to stand there?
二人はいつまでそうしてるつもり
"How long"?
いつまでってことは　いつから見てた
How long have you been standing there?
Long enough to hear all the embarrassing bits, I guess.
聞いたは神田君が死にたくなるところからかな
Never mind, then. I don't want to know.
じゃ言わなくていい
Here.
これで　大事なものでしょう ほっとしてたよ
It's important, right?
You dropped it.
Aoyama.
青山
Yes?
何
Will you help me rehearse my presentation again?
またプレゼンの練習　手伝ってくれるか
Of course!
もちろん
私も　私も手伝う
Me too!
I'll help you too!
I've been unable to move past
arifureta kanjou kara
a
ri
fu
re
ta
ka
n
jou
ka
ra
these humdrum emotions.
sotsugyou mo dekitenakute
so
tsu
gyo
u
mo
de
ki
te
na
ku
te
It keeps me up at night.
nemurenai
ne
mu
re
na
i
Drenched in the sudden rain,
totsuzen no ame nukarunda
to
tsu
ze
n
no
a
me
nu
ka
ru
n
da
those boots glisten.
ano kutsu wa mabataki suru
a
no
ku
tsu
wa
ma
ba
ta
ki
su
ru
Surely I've come to terms
kimi no sekai wo kitto
ki
mi
no
se
ka
i
wo
ki
t
to
with your world.
uketometeiru
u
ke
to
me
te
i
ru
Your reality,
kimi no riaru
ki
mi
no
ri
a
ru
my perspective.
boku no shisen
bo
ku
no
shi
se
n
They may not match up, but still...
dokoka chigau to shitemo
do
ko
ka
chi
ga
u
to
shi
te
mo
I'm not going to let you become
ano kutabireta T-shatsu mitai ni
a
no
ku
ta
bi
re
ta
T-
sha
tsu
mi
ta
i
ni
like that worn-out T-shirt.
sasenai kara
sa
se
na
i
ka
ra
prime number
prime
num
ber
There's not a single
sekai ni dore
se
ka
i
ni
do
re
other one like it in the world.
hitotsu to shite onaji mono ga nai
hi
to
tsu
shi
te
o
na
ji
mo
no
ga
nai
I don't have to force myself to fill
kokoro no kuuhaku wo muri ni
ko
ro
no
kuu
ha
ku
wo
mu
ri
ni
the void in my heart, do I?
umenakutemo ii ne
u
me
na
ku
te
mo
i
ne
It doesn't matter if countless people
takusan no dareka no kioku ni
ta
ku
sa
n
no
da
re
ka
no
ki
o
ku
ni
hold me in their memories.
nokosarete iru yori mo
no
ko
sa
re
te
i
ru
yo
ri
mo
I'd rather become
yane no ue
ya
ne
no
u
e
a sky for you, over the rooftops.
kimi dake no sora ni naritai
ki
mi
da
ke
no
so
ra
ni
na
ri
ta
i
You're heavy...
重い
That's mean.
ひどいわ
What do we do? It's pitch black.
どうしよう　真っ暗
Maybe they're engaging in "nighttime activities"?
もしかして　夜の営み中
Don't put it so bluntly!
そうなはっきり言うならあかん
In any case, I'm going inside.
とにかく俺は入るぞ
へえ
I can't take it any longer...
もう限界
Huh? It's unlocked—
かぎ　かかって
Misaki-senpai?
美咲先輩
I tried.
私　がんばったよ
I tried really hard to be his lover.
恋人になりたいってがんばったんだもん　 でも
But...
As I am now, I can't love you the way I should.
今の俺は　お前を大切にできない
You're fine the way you are right now.
いいよ　それでも
Not in the slightest.
いいわけないだろう
Then what do you want me to do?
だったら私どうすればいいの
You don't have to do anything.
何もしなくていい　お前は　そのままでいいんだ
You're fine the way you are.
I don't understand...
わかんない　わかんないよ
I don't understand what you're saying...
仁のいってること
Just stay the way you are.
お前はそのままでいってくれ
Stay the Misaki that I love.
俺の好きな美咲のままで
I don't get it...
おかしいよ
Jin was so gentle.
仁はすごく優しかった
But...
でも　違うんだよ
That's not it...
Tonight, I...
今日は私は　私は仁に傷つけてほしかったんだよ
I wanted to be hurt by Jin!
Coming back home with three new daughters-in-law, huh?
娘さんを三人もつれての里帰りが
Where's My Usual Self?
Sons grow up in a blink of the eye with just a little stimulation, I see.
息子と言うのは
ちょっとした刺激を与えるだけで
あというまに大きくなるものだな
So it goes.
しみじみ